Edward Bruce
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Edward Bruce papers
1902-1960 (bulk 1932-1942)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Bruce, Edward
8.5 linear feet
The Edward Bruce papers measure 8.5 linear feet and date from 1902 to 1960, with the bulk of the material dating from 1932 to 1942. The collection documents Bruce's work as an artist, art collector, exhibition juror, and federal government art administrator, particularly his tenure as Director of the U. S. Treasury Department's Section of Fine Arts. Well over one-half of the collection consists of extensive correspondence with artists, art collectors and dealers, arts associations, galleries, and government officials, including President and Mrs. Franklin D. Roosevelt.
Provenance
The Edward Bruce papers were donated by Margaret (Peggy) Bruce, Edward Bruce's wife, in 1962. Additional printed material, financial records, and photographs of artwork were donated by Mrs. Bruce's niece, Maria Ealand in 1979.
Separated Material
A book Art in Federal Buildings by Forbes Watson and Edward Bruce was donated to AAA with Bruce's papers and microfilmed with the rest of collection on Microfilm Reel D91-D92, and then transferred to the Smithsonian American Art Museum Library.
Related Material
Other resources in the Archives relating to Edward Bruce include an oral history interview with Margaret (Peggy) Bruce on October 11, 1963 conducted by Harlan Phillips. Miscellaneous Manuscript Collections include one file of material, 1933-1960, concerning Edward Bruce that was donated by the U.S. General Services Administration in 1986 and microfilmed on reel 3960.
Also available at the Archives are two collections of records loaned by the U.S. National Archives from their Public Buildings Administration records and the records of the Public Works of Art Project for microfilming by the Archives. Microfilm reels DC1-DC 13 and DC116-DC128 contain Edward Bruce's files and correspondence, respectively.
Alternative Forms Available
Much of the collection is available on 35 mm microfilm reels D82-D92 and reel 1817 at Archives of American Art offices, and for interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of material described in this finding aid closely matches the arrangement of the microfilm, but not for all of the files. When known, notations have been made at the folder level in the container listing to the corresponding reel and frame numbers.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. The collection is partially microfilmed. Use of material not microfilmed requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Edward Bruce was born in 1879 in Dover Plains, New York. Though he enjoyed painting at a young age, he pursued a career in law and graduated from Columbia Law School in 1904. He practiced law in New York and in Manila, Philippines and was actively involved in international issues. He became president of the Pacific Development Corporation of California, was a lobbyist for the Philippine Independence Bill, and, in 1933, attended the London Economic Conference as a silver expert.
In 1923 Bruce gave up his career in law and business and began to paint, particularly landscapes. He and his wife Peggy spent the next six years in Anticoli Carrado, Italy where he studied painting from his friend and fellow artist Maurice Sterne. Bruce returned to the United States in 1929 and settled in California, exhibiting his artwork to much public and critical praise. In addition, Bruce was an avid collector of Chinese art.
In 1933 Bruce was appointed Chief of the newly established Public Works of Art Project, a federal government New Deal program within the U.S. Treasury Department, that employed artists to decorate numerous public buildings and parks. Though this federal program lasted less than a year, Bruce worked with Secretary of the Treasury Henry Morgenthau, Jr., to establish the Treasury Department's Section of Painting and Sculpture in 1934 - later renamed the Section of Fine Arts in 1938. Bruce was appointed Director of the department and played a primary role in securing federal government support for American artists. In 1940 he was appointed to the Commission of Fine Arts by President Franklin Delano Roosevelt.
Bruce received many honors and awards during his lifetime both for his work as an artist and for his capable and dedicated administration of federal arts programs. Despite poor health, he continued his work for the Section of Fine Arts until shortly before his death in 1943.
Scope and Content Note
The Edward Bruce papers measure 8.5 linear feet and date from 1902 to 1960, with the bulk of the material dating from 1932 to 1942. The collection documents Bruce's work as an artist, art collector, exhibition juror, and federal government art administrator, particularly his tenure as Director of the U. S. Treasury Department's Section of Fine Arts. Well over one-half of the collection consists of extensive correspondence with many notable artists and government officials. Also found is scattered biographical material, office diaries and speeches, personal financial material, printed material, four scrapbooks, and photographs.
A small amount of biographical material includes birth records and many awards and certificates. Bruce's correspondence files comprise over half of this collection, containing correspondence with family, friends, artists, art organizations, political figures, museums, art galleries, and government agencies. Found within the files is extensive correspondence with friend and art critic Leo Stein and artist friend Maurice Sterne. Additional artists Bruce corresponded with include George Biddle, Adrian Dornbush, and Olin Dows. Also included is correspondence documenting his career as Chief of the Treasury Department's Section of Fine Arts with government colleagues and officials, much of it concerning his role on various federal arts committees, including the Commission of Fine Arts. There is also extensive correspondence with Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt concerning federal and public art projects.
Writings include office diaries and notebooks containing notes, addresses, lists of Section of Fine Arts projects, and dated work entries. There are copies of numerous written speeches given by Bruce on the importance of art, public art projects, and political issues. Financial material consists of a small number of items documenting Bruce's financial activity such as tax and insurance records, bills, a cash book, and house leases. Printed material documents Edward Bruce's career as an artist and federal arts projects and programs. Found are news clippings and magazine articles, exhibition catalogs, brochures, bulletins from the Section of Fine Arts, published speeches, and miscellaneous publications. Four scrapbooks contain news clippings, letters, photographs, and other printed material highlighting Bruce's career.
Extensive photographs include photographs of Bruce's artwork, portraits of Bruce, the Bruces with family and with friends and at many special events, including an NBC radio broadcast and at an exhibition with Eleanor Roosevelt. There are also photographs taken by Bruce during his travels and while living in Anticoli Carrado, Italy.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects-Topical:
United States -- Dept. of the Treasury -- Section of Fine Arts; Art -- Collectors and collecting -- Washington (D.C.); Art, Modern--20th century--United States; Arts administrators -- Washington (D.C.); Painters -- Washington (D.C.)
Types of Materials:
Photographs; Scrapbooks
Names:
Biddle, George, 1885-; Dornbush, Adrian, 1900-; Dows, Olin, 1904-; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Stein, Leo, 1872-1947; Sterne, Maurice, 1878-1957
Arrangement
The Edward Bruce collection is arranged into 7 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, circa 1904-1938 (Box 1, OV 11; 3 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, circa 1921-1957 (Boxes 1-6; 5.5 linear feet)
Series 3: Writings, circa 1931-1942 (Box 6; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 4: Financial Material, circa 1909-1913, circa 1928-1943(Box 6, 0.3 linear feet)
Series 5: Printed Material, circa 1919, circa 1926-1943, 1960 (Box 7, 0.5 linear feet)
Series 6: Scrapbooks, 1922-1941 (Box 7-8; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 7: Photographs, circa 1902-1943 (Box 7, 9-10; 1.0 linear foot)
Although the collection no longer matches the exact filmed order, large groups of materials have been maintained in film order, particularly the correspondence. Microfilm reel and frame number notations are provided at the folder level when known.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, circa 1904-1938, Series 1:; (Box 1, OV 11; 3 folders)
  Biographical Material includes Edward Bruce's Diploma from Columbia University and a certificate appointing him to the Commission of Fine Arts. Also in this series are biographical documents verifying his birth.
  - Awards and Certificates, 1904-1938, (See also OV 11; unfilmed) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Documents, 1918, 1923, undated, (Reel D90:930-931) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1904-1938, (See also Box 1, F1) (Box OV 11)
- Correspondence, circa 1921-1957, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-6; 5.5 linear feet)
  Well over one-half of the collection is comprised of Edward Bruce's personal and professional correspondence, the bulk of which dates from 1932 to 1942, the period Bruce worked as the Chief of the Treasury Department's Section of Fine Arts. His official work and activities in this capacity are well-documented through an abundance of correspondence with other government officials and colleagues concerning the Section of Fine Art's programs, projects, and commissions, and other federal government art programs and public art projects. There is also correspondence relating to Bruce's role on the Mount Rushmore National Memorial Commission. Bruce's extensive correspondence with Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Eleanor Roosevelt about public art projects is found in this series.
  There is also personal and business correspondence with many artists, dealers, museums, galleries, and arts associations. A great deal of this correspondence concerns Bruce's own artwork, his personal art collection, and his role as a juror for many art exhibitions.
  The Correspondence series is arranged into 2 subseries:
  Subseries 2.1: Alphabetical Correspondence, circa 1921-1957
  Subseries 2.2: Chronological Correspondence, circa 1928-1942
  - Alphabetical Correspondence, circa 1921-1957, Subseries 2.1:
    Found here is Bruce's correspondence with his family and many prominent friends, including art collector Samuel Lewisohn, art critic Leo Stein, and former Chief Justice Harlan F. Stone. Also found is correspondence documenting Bruce's career as an artist. He corresponded with art associations including the American Association of Museums and the National Academy of Design, art collectors and dealers such as A. W. Bahr and Albert Barnes, and with art museums and galleries concerning the exhibition of his work and as a juror for exhibitions, including the Century Club, Corcoran Gallery of Art, and the Whitney Museum of American Art. Also included is correspondence regarding the Friedsam Gold Metal Bruce was awarded from the Architectural League of New York in 1938.
    Among the artists Bruce corresponded with are George Biddle, Oscar Bleumner, Adrian Dornbush, Olin Dows, Waldo Peirce, Henry Varnum Poor, Boardman Robinson, Maurice Sterne, Ralph Stackpole, and Victor Hammer. This series also includes Bruce's correspondence with Milch Galleries, which represented his artwork, and correspondence about his Chinese art collection.
    The alphabetical correspondence provides extensive documentation of Bruce's career as the Chief of the Treasury Department's Section of Fine Arts. There is correspondence with the Secretary of the Treasury Henry Morgenthau, business correspondence with colleagues in the Section, including Edward Rowan and Inslee Hopper, and correspondence with government officials Archibald MacLeish and Frederic A. Delano. Also included in this series is Bruce's extensive correspondence with Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Eleanor Roosevelt, keeping them informed of the various public art projects. Bruce's professional correspondence with government officials and businessmen about Philippine independence and its economy is also found here.
    - A, Miscellaneous, 1932-1941, undated, (Reel D82:1-74) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adams, Katherine, 1937, (Reel D82:2-7) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Alanson, Bertram E., 1935-1939, undated, (Reel D82:75-84) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Albert, Franklin E., 1937, (Reel D82:8-15) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Alunan, Raphael R. (see also Philippine Sugar Association), 1934, (Reel D82:85-93) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - American Association of Museums, 1939-1940, (Reel D82:94-110) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - American Olympic Association, 1921-1935, (Reel D82:30-44) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - American Planning and Civic Association, 1936-1937, (Reel D82:111-119) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Anderson, John & Margaret, 1932-1943, undated, (Reel D82:120-165) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Architectural League of New York, 1934-1941, (4 folders; Reel D82:166-340) (Box 1, Folder 12-15)
    - Auslander, Joseph, 1938-1941, (Reel D82:64-70) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - B, Miscellaneous: Ba-Bas, 1933-1941, (Reel D82:341-382) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - B, Miscellaneous: Bat-Be, 1932-1941, (Reel D82:383-448) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - B, Miscellaneous: Bi-Bl, 1933-1942, (Reel D82:449-479) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - B, Miscellaneous: Bo-Br, 1931-1942, (Reel D82:480-543) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - B, Miscellaneous: Bu, 1933-1942, (Reel D82:551-584 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bahr, A. W., 1932-1942, undated, (4 folders; Reel D82:585-753) (Box 1, Folder 22-25)
    - Baltimore Evening Sun, 1938, (Reel D82:754-760) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bankers Trust Company, 1930-1937, (2 folders; Reel D82:761-806) (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
    - Barker, Burt Brown, 1934-1938, (Reel D82:807-824) (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Barnes, Albert C., 1939-1941, (Reel D82:825-831) (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Beal, Gifford, 1939, 1941, (Reel D82:832-836) (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Beal, Lester, 1941, (Reel D82:393-399) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Beard, Mary (Mrs. Charles), 1939, (Reel D82:837-839) (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Bender, Albert M., 1937-1941, (Reel D82:840-891) (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Benno, B. G., 1935, 1940, (Reel D82:410-417) (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Bethune-Cookman College, 1940, (Reel D82:437-446) (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Biddle, George, 1934-1940, (2 folders; Reel D82:892-1051) (Box 1, Folder 37-38)
    - Birnbaum, Martin, 1935-1940, (Reel D82:1055-1077) (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Blanch, Lucille & Arnold, 1932-1941, (Reel D82:1078-1087) (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Bliss, Robert Woods & Mildred, 1939-1940, (Reel D82:1088-1102) (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Bluemner, Oscar, 1934-1938, (Reel D82:1103-1151) (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Bowditch, Edward (Peter), 1938-1941, undated, (Reel D82:1152-1166) (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Bringier, Jane, 1940-1941, (Reel D82:506-516) (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Brown, Adele, 1940-1942, (Reel D82:1167-1171) (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Brownell, Francis H., 1933, 1938, (Reel D82:533-542) (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Bruce, Alfred, 1935-1941, undated, (2 folders; Reel D82:1172-1282) (Box 1, Folder 47-48)
    - Bruce, Margaret S. (Mrs. Edward), 1939-1957, (Reel D83:1035-1054) (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Bruce, John M. (Jack), 1935-1942, undated, (Reel D83:1056-1117) (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Bruce, Osborn, 1931-1933, undated, (Reel D83:1118-1129, 1166-1174) (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Bruce, Peter, 1933, 1939, (Reel D83:1160-1165) (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Bruce, Randolph, 1933-1941, (Reel D83:1130-1159, 1175-1211) (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Bruner, Raymond & Louisa, 1937, 1941, (Reel D82:544-550) (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Bunker, Ellsworth, 1935-1941, (2 folders; Reel D84:342-424) (Box 1, Folder 55-56)
    - Burchfield, Charles, 1941, (Reel D84:425-430) (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - C, Miscellaneous: Ca-Ch, 1934-1941, (Reel D84:431-483) (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - C, Miscellaneous: Cl-Co, 1934-1941, (Reel D84:484-543) (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - C, Miscellaneous: Cr-Cu, 1929-1942, (Reel D84:552-583) (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Cardozo Memorial, 1932-1938, (2 folders; Reel D84:584-650) (Box 1, Folder 61-62)
    - Carey, William F. & Ocean, 1934-1941, undated, (2 folders; Reel D84:651-749) (Box 1, Folder 63-64)
    - Carnegie Institute, 1933-1941, (4 folders; Reel D84:750-903) (Box 1, Folder 65-68)
    - Celotex Corporation, 1938, (Reel D84:459-465) (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Century Association, 1938-1939, 1942, (Reel D84:904-919) (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Century Club Exhibition, 1933-1934, (2 folders; Reel D84:920-987) (Box 1, Folder 71-72)
    - Chambers, Eunice, 1938, (Reel D84:466-472) (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Chinese Art Collection, 1938-1942,undated, (Reel D83:882-926) (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Christmas Cards, 1938, undated, (Reel D82:864-881) (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Christmas Party, 1938-1941, (2 folders; Reel D84:994-1012, 1018-1063, 1090-1134) (Box 1, Folder 76-77)
    - Clark, Victor, 1933-1941, (4 folders; Reel D84:1135-1339) (Box 1, Folder 78-81)
    - Columbia University, 1937, (Reel D84:1340-1359) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Commission of Fine Arts, 1936-1942, (12 folders; Reel D84:1360-1679; D85:1-153) (Box 2, Folder 2-13)
    - Cooke, Richard A., 1933-1940, (Reel D85:154-186) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1932-1941, (2 folders; Reel D85:187-242) (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
    - Cosgrave, John O'Hara & Jessica, 1932-1941, (5 folders; Reel D85:243-500) (Box 2, Folder 17-21)
    - Cosmos Club, 1935-1937, (Reel D84:538-542) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Coyle, David Cushman, 1939-1941, (Reel D85:501-506) (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Cram, William C., Jr., 1934-1937, (Reel D85:507-519) (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Craton, Ann, 1934, (Reel D84:544-551) (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Creative Art (Magazine), 1932-1933, (Reel D85:520-534) (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Cunningham, John, 1929-1939, (Reel D85:535-549) (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Curry, John Steuart, 1935, 1938-1940, (Reel D84:571-577; D85:550-562) (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Curtis, J. Gerry, 1937-1938, undated, (Reel D84:578-582) (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Cutting, Suydam & Helen, 1933-1940, (Reel D85:563-593) (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - D, Miscellaneous: Da-De, 1934-1941, (Reel D85:594-660) (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - D, Miscellaneous: Di-Du, 1933-1941, (Reel D85:661-699) (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Delano, Frederic A., 1933-1942, (3 folders; Reel D85:700-875) (Box 2, Folder 33-35)
    - Delano, William Adams, 1935-1942, (Reel D85:625-632) (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Democratic National Committee, 1936-1942, (2 folders; Reel D85:876-930) (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
    - Denman, Leslie Van Ness, 1936-1939, (Reel D85:633-655) (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Department of Agriculture, 1937-1940, (Reel D85:931-948) (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Department of the Interior, 1939, (Reel D85:964-965) (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Department of Justice, 1937-1941, (Reel D85:955-963) (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Dornbush, Adrian, 1935-1940, (2 folders; Reel D85:1179-1253) (Box 2, Folder 43-44)
    - Dorr, Goldthwaite H., 1938-1939, (Reel D85:1254-1259) (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Dougherty, Paul, 1932, 1935-1937, (Reel D85:673-684) (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Dows, Olin, 1936-1942, (7 folders; Reel D85:1260-1468; D86:1-230) (Box 2, Folder 47-53)
    - E, Miscellaneous, 1935-1942, (Reel D86:231-283) (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Ealand, Maria, 1933-1941, undated, (2 folders; Reel D86:284-374) (Box 2, Folder 55-56)
    - Economic Conference, 1932-1933, (Reel D86:375-388) (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Egan, Martin, 1933-1937, (Reel D86:234-243) (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Ehrman, Alfred, 1933-1941, (4 folders; Reel D86:389-582) (Box 2, Folder 59-62)
    - Eisele, Louisa, 1936-1937, (Reel D86:244-254) (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Embury, Aymar II, 1935-1937, (Reel D86:265-271) (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - F, Miscellaneous: Fa-Fe, 1934-1941, (Reel D86:583-603 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - F, Miscellaneous: Fi-Fl, 1935-1941, (Reel D86:604-637) (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - F, Miscellaneous: Fo-Fu, 1935-1942, (Reel D86:638-696) (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Federal Security Agency, 1940-1941, (Reel D86:697-702) (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Federal Works Agency, 1935-1941, (Reel D86:703-747) (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Finch School, 1935, (Reel D86:748-753) (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Flaherty, Robert, 1934-1941, (Reel D86:619-633) (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Forbes, Cameron, 1933-1941, (Reel D86:754-772) (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Fortune Magazine, 1933-1939, undated, (2 folders; Reel D86:773-832) (Box 2, Folder 73-74)
    - Frank, Jerome, 1934-1940, (Reel D86:670-677) (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1940, (Reel D86:833-848) (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Friedman, Arnold, 1938-1941, (Reel D86:849-863) (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - G, Miscellaneous, 1935-1941, undated, (Reel D86:864-908) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Gans, Howard, 1936-1942, (2 folders; Reel D86:909-1004) (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
    - Gaston, Herbert E. (Department of Treasury), 1935-1941, (Reel D85:1170-1176) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Gates, Margaret and Robert, undated, (Reel D86:1005-1027) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Gerstle, William Lewis, 1937-1940, (Reel D86:879-889) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - H, Miscellaneous: Ha, 1935-1942, (Reel D86:1028-1083) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - H, Miscellaneous: He-Hu, 1929-1942, (Reel D86:1084-1130) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Hammer, Victor, 1930-1941, (2 folders; Reel D86:1131-1227) (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
    - Harvard University, 1938, (2 folders; Reel D86:1228-1291) (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
    - Hatch, John Davis, Jr., 1934-1939, (Reel D86:1039-1064) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Henderson, Leon, 1939-1942, (Reel D86:1092-1098) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Hoffman, William H., 1935-1938, (Reel D86:1102-1109) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Hopkins, Harry L. (Department of Commerce), 1934-1940, (Reel D85:949-954) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Hopper, Inslee, 1935-1945, (8 folders; Reel D86:1292-1614) (Box 3, Folder 17-24)
    - House in Peru, Vermont, 1936-1937, (Reel D88:258-261) (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Housh, Chester, 1941-1942, (Reel D86:1615-1625) (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Hull, Cordell (Department of State), 1935-1942, (Reel D85:966-983; D86:1626-1668) (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - J, Miscellaneous, 1934-1943, undated, (Reel D87:246-290) (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Jacobson, Carl, 1935-1940, (Reel D87:247-256) (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - James, Henry, 1936-1942, (Reel D87:307-357) (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Jaqua, Ernest J., 1938-1939, (Reel D87:291-306, 358-374) (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Key West Project, 1935-1936, (Reel D87:375-429) (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Lawrence, W. H., 1935-1942, (4 folders; Reel D87:430-567) (Box 3, Folder 33-36)
    - Leffingwell, Russell, 1937-1940, (Reel D87:568-580) (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Lewis, Sir Wilmott, 1935-1936, (Reel D87:581-606) (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lewisohn, Samuel A., 1931-1941, (2 folders; Reel D87:607-659) (Box 3, Folder 39-40)
    - Lind, K. B., 1932-1933, (Reel D87:660-666) (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Lindeberg, Harry, 1935, undated, (Reel D87:667-668) (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Ma-Me, 1933-1942, (Reel D87:687-745) (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - M, Miscellaneous: Mi-My, 1932-1942, (Reel D87:746-804) (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Mc, Miscellaneous, 1933-1942, (Reel D87:669-686) (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - McReynolds, W. H., 1938-1942, (Reel D90:708-720) (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Mack, Harold, 1932-1940, (Reel D87:805-860) (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1939-1942, (2 folders; Reel D87:861-906) (Box 3, Folder 48-49)
    - Macon, Georgia, Art Association, 1935, (Reel D87:907-910) (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Manship, Paul, 1933-1940, (Reel D87:699-706) (Box 3, Folder 51)